本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 黑色风车 小白兔 王老猫 日月 JoJo
校对： 小坏玩意儿   后期： 深影后期组
法律面前并非人人平等
There is no equality before the law.
前情提要
那是我的第一条真理
That is my first truth.
- 结束了 夏洛特 - 你是我的全部
- 我不能回家 - 如果愿意就留下来
- I cant go home. - Stay here if you want.
你说过你的第二条真理已经开始了
You said that your second truth has begun.
让・克劳德・戴尔普兰克 退伍军人
Jean-Claude Delplanque. Retired soldier.
- 老人有什么用 - 离开那里
- What good are old people? - Get out of there.
他们只会消耗我们的纳税
They consume nothing, except our taxes.
冬天老人们会怎样
What happens to old people in winter?
马上就能看到
Soon we will see
那些老英雄们在法国是多么受照顾
how much old heroes are cared for in France.
我们认为他是在某个工业冷库里
We think hes in some kind of industrial cold store
而且知道他位于
and we know he has to be
离加莱市中心两小时车程范围之内
within two hours of central Calais.
所以 打电话给所有
So, ring round all the companies
提供工业冷库的公司
that supply these cold stores.
获取冷库的平均使用寿命
Get the average life span of them
得到所有在这个时间段
and then get the details of all units
和这个范围之内
installed within this time frame
提供冷库的单位的详细信息 好吗
and within this radius. Yeah?
我们知道那时他即将被驱逐...
We know he was about to be evicted...
是因为这个原因
so was it about that,
还是因为更私人的原因
or was it something more personal,
关于他过去的一些事...
something in his past...?
我们能联系到一个人 曾与他是一个团的战友
We have a contact to talk to now at his old regiment.
我们在等一位少校的答复
We are waiting to hear back from a Major.
他和死去的十四个退休人员有什么关系
And how is he connected to our 14 dead pensioners?
还有那四个商人
How to the four businesspeople?
我们找到答案也就找到了真理杀手
We find the answers, we find TT.
我们要记住
We must remember,
他为了证明法律不公平
he murdered a prostitute
而杀了一个妓女
to highlight the inequality of the law.
他声称是自己干的
Well, he said he did.
但他是真理杀手
But hes the Truth Terrorist.
有趣
Funny.
警方认为人质让・克劳德・戴尔普兰克
被关在加莱方圆一百六十公里内的一个冷库里
还不确定他身在法国还是英国
但调查正围绕着法国展开
戴尔普兰克 一个退伍军人
正面临被冻死的危险
意想不到的是 真理杀手在其网站上
指出四个商界和金融界的名人
他说他们可以救让・克劳德・戴尔普兰克
下面是一则喜讯 里尔动物园欢庆
刚刚出生的...
- 所以要看情况 - 什么
- So it depends. - On?
年龄 体型 性别
Age, body type, sex.
我女朋友七月还开着暖气呢
My girlfriend still has the heating on in July.
实际上 女人比男人更耐严寒
Actually, women bear extreme cold better than men.
因为脂肪 她们脂肪更多
Its the fat - they have more of it.
我们倒回去看 他二十分钟前开始发抖
So we re-wound, he started shivering 20 minutes ago.
这就意味着他的体核温度下降了
Which would mean his core temperature has dropped
一到两度 鉴于他年事已高 假设是两度
between one and two degrees - hes old so lets say two.
下降两至四度 他会更加剧烈地颤抖
Between two and four hell start shivering more violently,
然后停止颤抖 这样消耗能量
then the shivering stops - its wasted energy -
随即进入低温状态
and the hypothermia sets in.
低于二十五度半他就会死
Below 25.5 he dies.
所以如果我们记下剧烈颤抖开始的时间
So if we mark when the violent shivering starts,
可以大致知道
we can get a rough idea
温度降低的速率
of the rate the temperature is decreasing.
并算出我们还剩下多少时间
And figure out how long we have.
# 到我怀里来 #
Venez dans mes bras
# 靠近我 亲爱的 #
Closer to me, dear
# 让我自己 #
Donnez-vous moi
# 抛开所有恐惧 #
Set aside all fear
# 一根红线 缠绕永远 #
Restons enlaces pour lternit
# 是的 你是我的 #
Yes, you shall be mine
# 直到地老天荒 #
Till the end of time
隧道谜案 第一季第四集
掏钱吧 金融巨鳄们
这真的是我们想说的吗
Is that really what we want to be saying?
它有什么问题
Whats wrong with it?
你不觉得这上面
Well, dont you think
写的有点简单吗
its a little more complicated than that?
...不觉得
Er... no.
还有这里 你应该看看竞争者的报道
And here, you should see the competition.
我写的和马修・帕里斯有得一拼
Mine is positively Matthew Parris in comparison.
英国作家
我开始觉得这一切
I guess Im just beginning to find it
有一点无聊了
all a little bit dull,
因为我们讨厌看到别人有哪怕一点儿收获
always implying that we hate anyone whos earned a bit.
这或许是因为你已经有了一点收获
That might be because youve earned a bit?
要记住的是 头儿
Its always worth remembering, boss,
我们的读者几乎全靠着
that our readers subsist almost entirely on
垃圾食品和嫉妒心来维持生存
a diet of saturated fat and envy.
- 还有偶尔开开车 - 好吧...
- And the occasional Wagon Wheel. - Fine...
那我们来挑战他们 让他们思考一下...
So lets challenge them, make em think a little bit...
如果他们愿意被挑战
If they wanted to be challenged
这会儿就不会看我们的文章了 不是吗
they really wouldnt be reading us now, would they?
他们只想看到他们自己的观点
What they want is to read their opinions,
- 是被打出来的 而不是涂鸦 - 好吧
but typed, not just in crayon. - Fine.
但是别变得无聊 丹尼
But dont get boring, Danny,
你可以恣意挑衅
you can be as gratuitously offensive as you like,
但我这儿可不养笨蛋
but I really dont pay you to be a dullard.
军队司令部 加莱市
情况更糟了 对吗
Thats worse than before, isnt it?
从他开始发抖 已经过去了两小时二十分钟
Two hours, 20 minutes since he started shivering
体温下降两度
to go down two degrees.
我们还剩...八九个小时
Gives us... eight, maybe nine hours?
是的...天啊
Yeah... Jesus.
怎么了
What?
瓦塞尔曼队长
Capitaine Wassermann.
你好
Bonjour.
英国探长卡尔・罗巴克
DCI Karl Roebuck from the UK.
你好
How do you do?
要不要来点儿咖啡
Can I get you some coffee?
戴尔普兰克于1956年18岁时加入帕拉斯
Delplanque joined the Paras in 1956 aged 18
一直在这个团服役
and stayed with the regiment all of his military career.
- 作为 - 一名二等兵
- As? - A Soldat de Deuxieme Class.
然后在部队里稳步晋升
Rose steadily through the ranks,
以军士长退役于...1997年
retiring as Adjutant Chef... in 1997
有着出色的服役记录
with an exemplary service record.
新闻里报道过三次
Mentioned in dispatches three times,
去过乍得 苏伊士 阿尔及利亚
did tours in Chad, Suez, Algeria,
伊拉克 期间获得过几枚勋章
Iraq and was awarded several medals over the years,
其中包括军事奖章和战斗十字奖章
including the Medaille Militaire and the Croix du Combattant.
什么时候授予的
When were the medals awarded?
十字奖章是表彰他在乍得的表现
He got the Croix for action in Chad.
另一枚是在阿尔及利亚
The other in Algeria.
有说明具体原因吗
Does it say what for, specifically?
我们这儿只有基础资料
Well, we only keep very basic files here,
- 剩下的都在仓库里 - 你能找出来吗
- the rest would all be in storage. - Could you find out?
你怎么在这儿
Why are you here?
什么
What?
你在这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
你同意我在这儿过夜的
You said I could sleep over.
你忘了吗
Dont you remember?
当时下着雨
It was raining.
你给了我一杯茶
You offered me a cup of tea.
我去做点早餐
Ill make some breakfast.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我要你的泰迪熊
I want your teddy!
- 那我要你的剑 拿过来吧 - 亚当
- And I want your sword so give it to me. - Adam.
把你的泰迪熊给我
Give me your teddy!
- 别烦我 - 亚当
- Just leave me alone! - Adam!
把你的泰迪熊给我
Give me your teddy.
- 不 - 好吧 哈哈 我自己也有
- No! - Fine! Ha-ha, Ive got mine!
怎么了
What?
你能照看他们二十分钟吗 拜托了
Can you just watch them for 20 minutes please,
我感觉不舒服
Im not feeling too good.
你需要一个女佣
You need an au pair.
不 我只是需要睡半小时
No. I just need half an hour to put my head down.
感激不尽
Id appreciate it.
好了 闭嘴...
Right, fucktards...
好吧 有人想喝热可可吗
Right, who wants hot chocolate?
我
Me!
- 马蒂厄 - 什么事
看到了吗
看到他头部的动作了吗
是 我看到了
他以前也这么做过 像是在暗示什么
稍等 我看一下
看那里
是我的错觉
还是这东西在震动
- 我能拉开... - 关着吧
- Shall I open the...? - Leave them.
我们不知道谁在监视着
We dont know whos watching.
吃点早餐吧
Have some breakfast.
有吃的东西吗
Do you have anything to eat?
有谷物或者吐司之类的吗
Any cereal or toast or something?
武士总在决战的前一天绝食
A samurai always fasts the day before he goes into battle.
我们想把震动转化成某种声音
能做到吗
声音就是震动 至少一部分是
想要复制他听到的声音
我们需要知道频率 振幅和波长
好 你能大致猜出是多少吗
如果时间充裕 我们能提供一些选项
多长时间
一到两天
一到两小时 可以吗
最后一个是舒斯特・里特的首席执行官
And finally the CEO of Schuster Ritter.
他们能救他
他们去年都赚了十亿美元
They all made billion dollar profits last year
尽管被指控有各类不法行为
despite various accusations of malpractice.
是...
Yeah...
所以在鲁伯特的案子中
So they all have some connection - or had,
他们都有着些联系 或者有过
in Jouberts case -
在关爱老年人这方面的联系
some connection with care for the elderly.
一些负面的联系
Some sort of negative connection.
他们马上就到
Theyve started to arrive.
好 有两个孩子的消息吗
Right. Anything on the kids?
我们正在询问他们的朋友
Were talking to their friends,
学校 任何认识他们的人
their schools, anyone who knew them,
到目前为止都没有人知道
so far no-one even knew
他们曾计划逃跑...
they were planning to run away...
更别说他们的去向了
我们知道他让那些孩子干了什么
We know what hes asked them to do,
但问题是...
but the question is...
他究竟想让他们做什么
what does he want them to do?
当我们把这问题解决了 我们就领先一步了
When we work that out, we get ahead of him.
通常来说 你们也知道现在的情况
Traditionally, as you know in this situation,
我们想问...
wed be asking you, you know...
有什么人怨恨你们吗
does anyone have a grudge against you?
但由于这可能包括西方世界的一半
But as that might include half of the western world,
我们直接说正题
well cut to the chase.
我们想让你们做的
What we want you to do is
和真理杀手要求的一样
exactly as the Truth Terrorist has requested.
一位警官建议我们
A police officer is suggesting
该尽快交赎金
we effectively pay a ransom?
你的惊讶正是我们这样建议的原因
Your surprise is exactly why were suggesting it.
这是他最不期望你做
Its the last thing he will expect you to do,
也是最不希望我们建议的事
the last thing he would expect us to advise.
这会迫使他改变
It will force him to adapt
他不得不回到戴尔普兰克先生身边
he will have to return to Monsieur Delplanque.
或者他也会坚持让他死去
Or maybe hed still let him die.
这是个游戏 有规则 他也必须遵守
This is a game, there are rules, he has to obey them too.
他会身不由己回到戴尔普兰克先生身边
He will have to return to Monsieur Delplanque
去关闭制冷系统
to turn off the refrigeration system.
到时如果我们知道了地点... 就能抓住他
And if we know where that is by then... well have him.
鲁伯特的遗孀在哪儿
Wheres Jouberts widow,
她作为其丈夫的受益人
doesnt she need to be involved in this
难道不需要参与到这里吗
as the beneficiary of his interests?
真理杀手在网上说
It said on TTs website
任何决定都由我们共同来做
any decision had to come from us all.
我们正在联系鲁伯特夫人
Were trying to contact Madame Joubert.
那么 我觉得我们应该谈谈
Well, then, I think maybe we need to talk.
就我们自己
On our own.
你认为他们会同意吗
Do you think theyll go for it?
如果我是他们的话 我不会同意
I wouldnt, if I were them.
怎么了
Whats going on?
他们是谁
Who are they?
上面写的什么
What does that say?
"拯救让・克劳德 杀掉有钱人"
"Save Jean-Claude, kill the fat cats."
他们怎么知道他们来了
How did they know theyre here?
操
Fuck.
我们当然不该付钱
Of course we shouldnt pay.
一分都不该给 那个男的明显就是个疯子
Not a fucking cent, the mans obviously a lunatic,
他谋杀了十四个无辜的退休老人
he murdered 14 innocent pensioners,
我们还要给他付钱
we pay him,
那么每个在欧洲的疯子
wed have every nutcase
都会绑架我们的商业同仁
in Europe kidnapping our business colleagues,
家人 还有我们 这个主意太荒谬了
our families, us - the ideas absurd.
但是我们真的能帮忙抓住
Except we could actually help catch
一个残忍的连环杀手
a brutal serial killer.
确实 你们想想
Exactly. How do you think
如果我们拒绝的话 公众会怎么想
itll play with the public if we say no?
迈克 你在养老院
Did you miss the six months of tabloid headlines
没看这六个月的小报头条吗
on your care homes, Michael?
如果你在达赖喇嘛嘴里拉屎
If you shat in the Dalai Llamas mouth,
你的公众形象就再坏不过了
your public image couldnt be any worse.
格鲁伯 你知道什么是格拉斯哥之吻吗
Do you know what a Glasgow kiss is, Gruber?
公众会一直恨我们 我们很成功
The public are always going to hate us, we are successful,
比他们生活得好
we have nicer lives than them,
我们做什么都不会改变这一点
nothing we ever do will change that.
你好 鲁伯特夫人 我是加莱警察局的塞西尔
你能尽快回复吗 谢谢
你来我的公寓做什么
你想要什么
出去 否则我报警了
你在和我丈夫胡搞吗
他这么跟你说的吗
好了 我们试试三千赫
猎鹰一号 呼叫指挥部
已到达老港口上方 现正开往布伦市
目前尚无可疑情况 完毕
八个未接电话
无号码
这些引人注目的名字里有夏洛特・鲁伯特
金融家阿兰・鲁伯特的遗孀 前者三天前自杀
有消息称其中三人现已到达加莱市警局总部
商讨解决方案
劳拉 已经十一点了
Laura? Its gone 11.
天啊 抱歉 亚当
Oh, God. Sorry, Adam.
就... 等我两分钟
Yeah, just... give me two minutes.
我还得去取药 省得医生找麻烦
I still pick them up so the doctors dont get cross.
但我已经不需要吃药了
But I dont need them any more.
他说
He said.
医生吗
The doctor?
"没人"
No-one.
医生已经不来了
The doctors dont come any more.
"没人"说我已经好了
No-one said Im better.
"没人"是他的名字
Thats his name.
好吧
Right.
是治什么的
So what were they for?
我以前只是有点困惑...
I just used to get a bit confused...
... 心烦意乱
... a bit distracted.
- 但现在不了 - 现在不了
- But not any more. - Not any more.
事实上
In fact,
现在我感觉前所未有的好
things feel better than they have in a long time.
你介意我去商店
do you mind if I went to the shops,
买点吃的东西吗
got something proper to eat?
我为什么要介意
Why would I mind?
来 我给你开门
Here. Ill let you out.
拯救戴尔普兰克 拯救戴尔普兰克
Delplanque liberer! Delplanque liberer!
我们已经试了各个频率和音高
没有可辨识出的声音
除了一个 播放
是火车
Thats a train.
没错 这是唯一有用的声音
Yes, its the only thing that makes sense.
所以我们知道他挨着一条铁路线
So, we know hes next to a train line.
如果我们从视频开始处
If we go back to the beginning of the feed,
记录下他所有的动作
mark all his movements,
就能整理出一个...
we can start compiling some kind of...
时间表 再让人通过这个声音
Timetable? And therell be someone who can identify
辨别出具体是哪种火车
the exact sort of train, just from that sound...
如果能查出火车的型号和发车时间表
And if we identify the type of train and frequency,
把它跟冷库的地点和时间表作比对
compare it to the cold store locations and timetables,
也许会有所发现
we may have something.
戴尔普兰克在1959年被授予奖章
Delplanque was awarded the medal in 1959,
表彰他救了一名
for saving the life of a fellow soldier
被阿尔及利亚战俘袭击的战友
who was being attacked by a prisoner - an Algerian.
战俘的儿子在战后
The prisoners son tried
对我们提起诉讼
to bring a case against us after the war.
艾哈迈德・阿巴斯... 是战俘还是他儿子
Ahmed Abbas... is that the prisoner or the son?
儿子 他现在六十出头
The boy, hes in his early 60s now.
是什么诉讼
And what was the case?
听着 所有这些都未被证实
Look, none of this was ever proved.
案件在1967年被驳回了
The case was thrown out in 1967.
是什么诉讼
What was the case?
阿巴斯声称戴尔普兰克杀了他父亲
Abbas claimed that Delplanque murdered his father
并且试图杀他
and tried to murder him.
在1958年2月 他和他父亲
Then, in February 1958, he and his father were abducted
被伞兵团成员绑架
by members of the Parachute Regiment,
"红魔鬼"伞兵团 英国特种部队之一
押进一架直升飞机
put into a helicopter
飞到五英里外的海上
and flown five miles out to sea.
戴尔普兰克和他的指挥官
Where Delplanque and his commanding officer
威胁要把儿子扔下去
threatened to throw the boy out.
他们把他拽到舱口时
As they held him over the edge,
父亲挣脱了
his father managed to break free
袭击了钳制他儿子的士兵
and attack the soldier holding him
戴尔普兰克把父亲拽开
and Delplanque pulled the father away
扔出了直升机
before throwing him out of the helicopter.
接着他自己也被戴尔普兰克扔了出去
He was then himself thrown out, also by Delplanque.
总之 要多少钱才足以表明我们在乎呢
How much is enough anyway, to show we care?
今早我给了一个乞丐
I gave a beggar a euro
一欧元去买咖啡... 这样够了吗
for a coffee this morning... was that enough?
你给了乞丐一欧元
You gave a beggar a euro?
没夸张... 我在表明立场
Not literally... Im making a point.
还是要一百欧 或一百万呢
Or is it 100 euros? Or a million?
听着 今天过后 有个人就会死
Look, end of the day, there is a man dying,
我们也许能救他的命
and we could save his life.
说得真冠冕堂皇 麦克博诺
Beautiful cliches, McBono.
好了 别吵了
All right, children.
我以为你不会回来了
I thought you werent coming back.
我买了些东西 还给你带了些绿茶
I did some shopping, got you some more green tea.
有人来过吗
Have you had a visitor?
"没人"
No-one.
那么他是... 来帮你的吗
So does he sort of... come in to help you, then?
是的
Oh, yes.
他让我看事情更清晰
He helps me see things more clearly.
他买给你的
And he bought you that?
是的
Yes.
礼物吗
A present?
- 我想是的 - 你不打开它吗
- I guess so. - Well, arent you going to open it?
我不能打开
Im not allowed to.
时机未到
Not yet.
好吧
Right.
什么特别的日子要到了吗
Special day coming up?
非常特别
Very.
我跟他说起了你
I told him all about you.
他非常感兴趣
He was very interested.
阿巴斯还在阿尔及利亚生活 他和家人
Abbas still lives in Algeria, and his family are about to
要上新闻声称戴尔普兰克活该被杀
go on the news to say Delplanque should be allowed to die.
不是很明智的做法
Not the smartest idea,
如果他们真跟他的绑架案有关联的话
if they had anything to do with his abduction.
看来不太可能
It seems pretty unlikely.
所以这显然是要
So this is obviously intended to
耍得所有人团团转
fuck with everyones head,
他设计给我们一个布局巧妙的道德谜题
some kind of exquisite moral conundrum hes set us.
会议室那边有消息吗
Any news from the conference room?
没有
No.
再等他们十分钟
Lets give them ten minutes,
然后我们就得推他们一把了
then put a rocket up their arse.
别担心 我们会抓住他的 相信我
Hey, dont worry, weve got him on the run, trust me.
为什么打我
Why did you hit me?
如果 他按规则出牌
IF he plays by the rules,
如果 警察能找到这个人被囚禁的地点
IF the police can find out where this man is being held,
如果 真理杀手认为我们捐赠的数目合理
IF the Truth Terrorist deems any donation enough.
太多假设因素了 抱歉 我退出
Too many fundamentals missing. Sorry, but Im out.
好吧 最终 虽然不情愿 但我确实觉得
Well, in the end, and very reluctantly, I actually think
我们再做什么都是不负责任的
it would be irresponsible for us to do anything else.
所以纯粹为我的家庭考虑 我也拒绝捐赠
So purely for the sake of my family, I say no too.
你什么都没说 鲁伯特女士
你怎么想
我想跟罗巴克探长谈谈
I think I want to speak to DCI Roebuck.
报告通过了
So, a report came through.
一位妇女发现了一对贫困母子
A woman found a distressed mother and child,
可能是非法移民来的
probably illegals,
在离这里十英里的一座小屋
in a cottage about ten miles from here.
当然 哪里都没有找到他们
No sign of them anywhere, of course.
猜猜谁是屋子的主人
And guess who the owner is?
或者你告诉我屋子的主人是谁
Or you tell me who the owner is.
是我们的老朋友 斯蒂芬・博蒙特先生
Its our old friend Mr Stephen Beaumont.
原来他中了奖
Turns out hes caked
他妈妈几年前去世后
and its one of a few places he inherited
屋子是他继承的一部分财产
when his mum died a few years back.
还有一处房产在锡利群岛和诺曼底
Theres also a place on the Scilly Isles and Normandy,
- 地理上讲... - 我知道诺曼底在哪
- which geographically is... - I know where Normandy is.
我刚刚想说 在加莱附近
Near Calais, I was going to say.
没那么近
Not that near.
挺近的
Near enough.
得看是诺曼底的哪个部分
Depends which part of Normandy.
反追踪 不管怎样 取证由我来负责
Back-tracking. Anyway, I took it upon myself to get
毕竟失踪者里
forensics in, considering the possible mispers
还有一个孩子
including a kid.
血液追踪 头发纤维和动机
So blood traces, hair fibres and spunk
都在进行化验和调查
all under the microscope now.
有新发现要打电话给我
Ring me if we get anything.
话说 诺曼底的大部分地区到加莱的距离
Most of Normandy is further away from Calais
比到伦敦的距离要更远一些
than it is from London, by the way.
非常抱歉你今天必须呆在这里
Im so sorry you had to be here today.
在过去几分钟 谣言已经出现
由真理杀手指定的几个大亨
没准备好付钱 救出让・克劳德・戴尔普兰克
他们的不情愿可能来源于不确切的报道
报道称戴尔普兰克可能与
五十年多前的谋杀和谋杀未遂案有关
喂
Yeah.
英国领退休金的人
UK pensioners
大概有一千万人 丹尼
comprise over ten million people, Daniel.
百分之二十的人过着贫穷的生活
20% of those live in poverty.
在法国 三分之一的自杀者出自领退休金的人
In France, pensioners make up a third of all suicides.
四分之一的人长期遭受虐待
One quarter experience regular abuse.
我真该感到幸运
Yeah, I should be so lucky.
这些富人们确实应该做些事情
Surely these very wealthy individuals could do something
来帮助他们 然而让・克劳德
to help them. And, Jean-Claude,
他拿着所有的钱
with all that money
无视他们的痛苦
they make off the back of their misery.
戴尔普兰克试图杀死一名儿童
Delplanque tried to kill a kid,
他们可以将他运到海中的冰山上
so they can ship him off to sea on an iceberg,
我的读者们可能会想
as far as my readers are concerned.
或许我们应该问问他 为什么会做出
Well, maybe we should ask why he might have done
如此残忍的事情
such a terrible thing.
他到底经历过怎样的痛苦
What pain he must have suffered himself
才会变得这么冷血
to become so unfeeling.
抱歉 我有些困惑
Sorry, Im confused.
我们仍在谈论戴尔普兰克 对吧
We are still talking about Delplanque, right?
最重要的是大家在谈论事情
That were talking at all is really whats important.
我们引发一场争论 大家交换意见
That we provoke a debate, that ideas are exchanged.
当然 帮个忙 好吗
Yeah, definitely. Help me out here, right?
帮我更了解你的立场
Help me understand your position a bit better
这样我可以向无知的人们解释
so I can explain it to the ignorant masses.
杀死十四个无辜领退休金的人
How exactly does killing 14 innocent pensioners
怎么能帮助他们的事业
help their cause?
丹尼 我们是一条绳上的蚂蚱
Were all in this together, Danny.
如果想创造一个更好的世界
We all have to make
必须要做出牺牲
sacrifices if were to create a better world.
但是这很复杂 不是吗
But it is complicated, isnt it?
太棒了... 更好的世界...
Thats great... better world...
期待能看到你的文章
Looking forward to reading you.
丹尼 我也是
Yeah, me too, Daniel.
我也是
Me too.
四分之一的老人遭受歧视
英国23%的老人遭受年龄歧视
7%的房屋中住有年逾85岁的老人
无法享受银行服务
年龄歧视是英国最常见的歧视形式
每年大约四万人卖房支付保障金
通常每周平均开销为七百欧元
法国85岁以上的人口
在2010至2020年将翻倍
被称为经济负担
提高税收 弥补老年护理的支出
我们联系了法国国营铁路公司
但是卢梭队长的儿子星期六在弗雷桑站工作
没有报酬
PBKA高速列车
巴黎-布鲁塞尔-科隆-阿姆斯特丹
你需要再听一遍吗
是PBKA
二万五千伏的电压 最高时速达三百公里
有两个引擎 提供八千八百千瓦的功率
就是PBKA
当在一万五千伏下操作时
输出功率会降至三千一百八十千瓦
会减小动力
你可以在火车的轨道上听出来
我们来听下一个吧
法国高速铁路
巴黎-法国东-德国南
我们只有86间冷藏库在铁路线附近
法国高速铁路和PBKA高速列车
只在这个区域的五个轨道行驶
其中肯定有一条经过冷藏库
那就有三十六种可能
我们要仔细检查时间表
将皮埃尔辨别出的火车
与让・克劳德听到的时间对比
- 多长时间 - 半个小时
也许那是她和别人生的孩子
Maybe it was her child with someone else.
不 他像是握新生儿一样握她的手
No. He was holding her as a newborn.
她的眼睛很像他 就是他的孩子
And I could see him in her eyes. It was his.
你知道...
And, you know...
...我可以原谅他的虚荣
...I could forgive him his vanity.
我可以原谅他无休止的欲望 追求更多的权利
I could forgive his need always for more - more power,
更多的钱 更多的尊重
more money, more respect.
甚至原谅他跟那个妓女鬼混 但和她生孩子
And even him fucking that tart, but giving her a child?
为了那个机会我已经乞求他二十年
When I had begged him for 20 years for that chance?
我永远都不会原谅他
I will never, ever forgive him that.
我想抹除他在我生命里的所有痕迹
And I want to wipe every trace of him from my life.
所有痕迹
Every trace.
这是一笔大数目
This is a very significant amount of money,
鲁伯特夫人
Madame Joubert,
你能百分之百确定吗
are you absolutely sure?
我确定
I'm sure.
你的丈夫深深地伤害了你 我很抱歉
现在她爱上我了
Now she loves me.
鲁伯特夫人决定作出捐赠
So Madame Joubert has decided to make a donation.
她知道并不是每个人都愿意捐赠
She understands not all of you feel the same way,
但是她愿意说这些钱都来自你们每个人
but she is willing to say that it comes from you all.
为了让真理杀手相信并释放戴尔普兰克
For TT to believe this and release Delplanque,
显然我们需要你们公开同意
obviously we need you to agree this publicly.
捐多少
How much?
大约两千七百万
27 million, give or take.
你为什么要这么做
Why would you do that?
重要的是
Look. The important thing is, notwithstanding
尽管你们对于同意他的要求保留意见
your principled reservations about acceding to his demands,
但现在只能赞同
that you just go along with this.
戴尔普兰克只有不到一个小时了
Delplanque has less than an hour.
我们正在接近他
Were closing in on his location.
我们找到他 抓住真理杀手 游戏就结束了
We find him, we get TT. Then the game is over.
到时你想说什么就说什么
Then you can say whatever you want.
我加入 没问题
Im in, no problem.
- 我也是 - 那么 让我们想想
- Me too. - Well, lets think about this,
我们都同意这将是不负责任的 对于...
we all agreed it would be irresponsible to...
安德森先生
You know, Mr Anderson,
底线是
the bottom line is,
如果你不能同意这些
if youre not able to go along with this,
我们可以让这幢楼以外的人都知道
we can let it be known outside
你不愿意合作
this building you were unwilling to co-operate.
- ... 我同意 - 谢谢
- Hey... Im in. - Thank you.
我的律师正在给慈善基金转账
My lawyers are transferring the money to the charity now.
很好 没时间了 已经告诉记者了 所以
Good, we couldnt wait. Weve told the press already, so...
他随时都能知道他的要求是否被满足了
hes gonna know any second now his demands have been met.
你还好吧
Are you all right?
是的 实际上很长一段时间
Yeah, actually I feel much better than I have
我没感觉这么好过了
for quite a while.
不管怎样 很高兴再见到你
Well, its been nice seeing you again, despite the circumstances.
再见
Bye.
他们已经把范围缩小为一两个位置了
They've narrowed it down to one of two places,
一个在桑加特外面
one just outside Sangatte
另一个在莱迪的工业园区
and one in an industrial park in Rety.
没有时间了 这两个地方我们都要去
Theres no time. Weve got to cover both.
你去这边 我们去这边
You take that one, well take that one.
- 你需要支援 - 是的
- You need back-up. - Yes.
- 支援到之前不要进去 - 好的!
- Do not go in until the back-up arrives. - OK!
- 爱丽丝... - 放心吧
- Elise... - I won't.
- 卡尔... - 知道了!
- Karl... - Yeah!
好的
支援十分钟内到
Back-up will be there in ten minutes.
走到头然后右转
Up the end, turn right.
就在那
That's it.
- 喂 查克斯 - 他刚刚下线 起作用了
- Yes, Chuks? - Hes just gone off line. It worked.
好的
All right.
十分钟可真漫长
Ten minutes is a long time.
现在还剩九分钟了
It's only nine now.
- 你要干什么 - 就下去看看
- What are you doing? - Just going to take a look.
我认为一个警察的主要职责就是
Its my opinion that the primary duty of a police officer
掩护好他的搭档
is to cover his colleague.
对吗?
Right?
- 只是说清楚 我是你的搭档 - 是的
- Just to be clear, I'm your colleague. - Yeah.
好了
Right.
爱丽丝
Elise.
没有电
No power.
塞西尔...
Cecile...
我们上
警察
该死
该死 爱丽丝 你没事吧 爱丽丝...
Oh fuck! Elise, are you all right? Elise...
该死 和我说话 他打到哪了
Shit! Speak to me. Where has he got you?
谢天谢地 好的 我去追他 你没事吧
Oh, thank God. OK, all right. I've gotta go, OK?
我没事
I'm OK.
他穿过那儿了
让・克劳德
Jean-Claude?
这需要救护车 没有发现孩子
他在下面 在往下面走
He's down there! He's coming down!
拜托
把他们拉出来
中心医院
我以为我们能抓到他
他全计划好了 甚至我们发现他时的逃生路线
你已经很接近了 继续施压 他会犯错误的
真的吗
- 孩子们怎么样 - 也没看到凶手的样子
- 他们很幸运 - 你这么认为吗
爱丽丝
你需要休息
像他一样
- 嗨 - 嗨 卡尔
- Hi.- Hey, Karl.
你看到他的样子了吗
Did you get a look at him?
我很好 谢谢你的关心
Im great, thanks for asking.
抱歉 你的睾丸还好吧
I'm sorry. How are your testicles?
感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
我带着这么个玩意 你觉得会怎么样
Well, Im wearing one of these things, how would you feel?
- 孩子们还好吧 - 他们很好
- Are the kids all right? - They're fine.
你的人呢
And your boys?
一个当场死亡 两个重伤
One died at the scene, two critical.
我不知道该说什么 对不起
I dont know what to say, I'm sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
我不知道我在等什么
Well, I dont know what I'm waiting for,
据我所知 他们能检查的都检查了
they've checked everything, as far as I know.
头 肋骨 睾丸
Head, ribs, balls.
- 我看看能不能让事情有点进展 - 好的
- I'll see if I can get things moving. - Good man.
他是故意打在你那个地方的吗
Did it feel deliberate that he hit you where he did?
就像他知道那是你最脆弱的地方
Like he knew you were vulnerable in that area?
我们那块都很脆弱
We're all vulnerable there.
快点好起来
Get well soon.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
我刚和我妈妈谈过
I just spoke to my mum finally.
我以为她会哭着求我回家
I thought she'd cry and beg for
但她只是...
me to come home again, you know, but she just...
她吓坏了 整个人勃然大怒
She just freaked. Went totally ballistic.
所以...
So...
我想再呆一晚或者... 可以吗
I'll stay another night or so... if that's OK?
你愿意呆多久都可以
Stay as long as you like.
过了明天这个公寓就是你的了
After tomorrow the flat is yours.
什么意思 我的
What do you mean, mine?
明天正义之剑将会挥动
Tomorrow the sword of justice will swing.
- 罗巴克夫人 - 是的
- Mrs Roebuck? - Yes.
爱丽丝・瓦塞尔曼 刑侦科
Elise Wassermann, Brigade Criminelle.
很高兴见到你 卡尔和我说了很多关于你的事
Ah. Nice to meet you. Karls told me a lot about you.
他说的 他都说什么了
He has? What's he said?
就说你们在一起工作
Oh, just that youre working together.
好的
Right.
我当时必须去救戴尔普兰克 你懂的
I had to help Delplanque, you understand that?
我也有义务要照顾他
I had a duty of care to him too.
是的 我明白
Yes, I understand.
我要进去了 很高兴见到你
I should go in. It was nice to meet you.
- 卡尔... - 嗨
- Oh, Karl... - Hey.
我没事 过来
It's all right. Come on.
慢点
Ow, easy.
对不起  真对不起
I'm sorry, sorry.
他对你做了什么
What did he do to you?
一切都运转良好
Everything's still in full working order.
怎么了
What?
发生这种事真的吓坏我了
It scares me when things like this happen.
我差点失去你
I could have lost you.
但你没有 不是吗 亲爱的
But you didn't, did you, love?
- 轻点 - 对不起
- Gently. - Sorry.